[
    {
        "question": "He cwæþ to him ðu wast ðæt ic ðe (<em>lufian</em>) ####⁠ — He said to him 'you know that I love you'",
        "correctAnswer": "lufie",
        "explanation": "Here 'lufian' is in the first person singular form '<em>lufie</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Eala ðu scippend heofones and eorþan! Ðu ðe on ðam ecan setle (<em>ricsian</em>) ####!⁠ — Oh you the creator of heaven and earth! You who reigns on the eternal seat!",
        "correctAnswer": "ricsast",
        "explanation": "Here 'ricsian' is in the second person singular form '<em>ricsast</em>' because the subject is 'You",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He (<em>gaderian</em>) #### sum gehwæde andgyt of ðære bec⁠ — He gathered some little information from the book",
        "correctAnswer": "gaderað|gaderaþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'gaderian' is in the third person singular form '<em>gaderað</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He het ond we (<em>andswarian</em>) ####⁠ — He calls and we answer",
        "correctAnswer": "andswariaþ|andswariað",
        "explanation": "Here 'andswarian' is in the first person plural form '<em>andswariað</em>' as the subject is 'We'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "andswaraþ",
                "explanation": "'Andswaraþ' is the third person form. Here 'he' is linked to the verb 'het'. 'Andswarian'should by in the plural form '<em>andswariað</em>' as its subject is 'We'."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Heofonas (<em>bodian</em>) #### oððe cýðaþ wuldor Godes⁠ — The heavens procalimed the glory of God",
        "correctAnswer": "bodiaþ|bodiað",
        "explanation": "Here 'bodian' is in the third person plural form '<em>bodiað</em>' as the subject is plural: 'the heavens'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>hatian</em>) #### hiera hieramonna unþeawas⁠ — They hate the vices of their subjects",
        "correctAnswer": "hatiaþ|hatiað",
        "explanation": "Here 'hatian' is in the first person singular past form '<em>hatiað</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>timbrian</em>) #### setl ðin⁠ — I built your seat",
        "correctAnswer": "timbrode ",
        "explanation": "Here 'timbrian' is in the first person singular past form '<em>timbrode</em>' because the subject is 'I",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "timbrie",
                "explanation": "'Timbrie' is the present singular form. Here 'timbrian' should be the past tense first person singular form '<em>timbrode</em>'"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "He eallum mannum (<em>lufian</em>) ####⁠ — He loved all men",
        "correctAnswer": "lufode",
        "explanation": "Here 'lufian' is in the third person singular past form '<em>lufode</em>' because the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðes apostol Iacobus (<em>bodian</em>) #### on Iudea lande⁠ — This apostle, Jacob, preached in the land of Judea",
        "correctAnswer": "bodode",
        "explanation": "Here 'bodian' is in the third person singular past form '<em>bodode</em>' because the subject is 'Jacob'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>timbrian</em>) #### langscipu mid æscum⁠ — They built the longships with ash trees",
        "correctAnswer": "timbredon",
        "explanation": "Here 'timbrian' is in the third person plural form '<em>timbredon</em>' because the subject is 'They'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On ðam dagum (<em>ricsian</em>) #### Æþelbyrht cyning ond his wif on Cantwarebyrig⁠ — On this day, Ethelbyrt and his wife reigned in Canterbury",
        "correctAnswer": "ricsodon",
        "explanation": "Here 'ricsian' is in the third person plural past form '<em>ricsodon</em>' because the subject is 'Ethelbert and his wife'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Him englas (<em>andswarian</em>) ####⁠ — The angels answered him",
        "correctAnswer": "andswaredon",
        "explanation": "Here 'andswarian' is in the third person singular past form '<em>andswaredon</em>' because the subject is 'The angels'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>gaderian</em>) #### ðyder eall ðæt me gewexen is⁠ — I gather thither all that is grown by me",
        "correctAnswer": "gaderie",
        "explanation": "Here 'gaderian' is in the first person singular form '<em>gaderie</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwy (<em>bodian</em>) #### þu mine rihtwisnesse mid þinne fulan muð⁠ — Why do you proclaim my justice with your foul mouth?",
        "correctAnswer": "bodast",
        "explanation": "Here 'bodian' is in the first person singular form '<em>bodast</em>' because the subject is 'you'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ne mæg middaneard eow hatian ac he (<em>hatian</em>) #### me⁠ — The world may not hate you, but he hates me",
        "correctAnswer": "hataþ|hatað",
        "explanation": "Here 'hatian' is in the third person singular form '<em>hataþ</em>' because the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie (<em>lufian</em>) #### mid lacum ða ðe læs agun⁠ — They show love with offerings to they who possess less",
        "correctAnswer": "lufiaþ|lufiað",
        "explanation": "Here 'lufian' is in the third person plural form '<em>lufiaþ</em>' because the subject is 'they'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ge (<em>andswarian</em>) #### to þone cyning⁠ — You answer to the king",
        "correctAnswer": "andswariaþ|andswariað",
        "explanation": "Here 'andswarian' is in the plural form '<em>andswariaþ</em>' because the subject is the plural 'you'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "We (<em>timbrian</em>) #### þisne ceastra⁠ — We built this city",
        "correctAnswer": "timbriaþ|timbriað",
        "explanation": "Here 'timbrian' is in the plural form '<em>timbriaþ</em>' because the subject is 'we'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>timbrian</em>) #### min hus on ðæm beorgum⁠ — I built my house in the mountains",
        "correctAnswer": "timbrode",
        "explanation": "Here 'timbrian' is in the first person singular past form '<em>timbrode</em>' because the subject is 'I'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Swa he (<em>ricsian</em>) #### and wið rihte wan ana wið eallum⁠ — So he ruled and challenged justice, one against all ",
        "correctAnswer": "ricsode",
        "explanation": "Here 'ricsian' is in the third person singular form '<em>ricsode</em>' because the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "ðæm ðe ær (<em>hatian</em>) #### eow⁠ — those that formerly hated you",
        "correctAnswer": "hatedon",
        "explanation": "Here 'hatian' is in the third person singular form '<em>hatedon</em>' because the subject is the demonstrative pronoun 'those'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt folc (<em>gaderian</em>) #### mid micle menio ðæra fugela⁠ — The people gathered a great number of the birds",
        "correctAnswer": "gaderode",
        "explanation": "Here 'gaderian' is in the third person plural form '<em>gaderode</em>' because the subject is 'the folk'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie hine (<em>lufian</em>) #### lease muðe⁠ — They loved him falsely with their mouth",
        "correctAnswer": "lufodon",
        "explanation": "Here 'lufian' is in the third person singular form '<em>lufodon</em>' because the subject is 'they'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ymb Bethleem (<em>bodian</em>) #### englas ðæt acenned wæs Crist on eorþan⁠ — Angels announced throughout Bethlehem that Christ was born on earth",
        "correctAnswer": "bododon",
        "explanation": "Here 'bodian' is in the third person plural past form '<em>bododon</em>' because the subject is 'angels'",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "bodiaþ",
                "explanation": "'Bodiaþ' is the present form. Here 'bodian' should be the past tense plural form '<em>bododon</em>'"
            }
        ]
    }
]